Sandeep Reddy Salkuti

816-286-0095 | salkutisandeep222@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/sandeepreddysalkuti | github.com/sandeepsalkuti

Summary

Experienced software engineer around 3 years of industry experience with passion for developing innovative programs that expedite the efficiency and effectiveness of organizational success. Actively seeking Full time opportunities in the area of software development.

EDUCATION

University of Missouri-Kansas City

Jawaharlal Nehru Technological University

Kansas City, MO

Masters in Computer Science

Graduated May 2021 Hyderabad, India

Bachelors in Computer Science

Graduated May 2018

Experience

Software Developer

Aug 2021 – Present

Tata Consultancy Services

Irving, USA

- Developed an in-built dashboard application which populates the data in the UI by reading an excel file along with plotting the data using apexcharts. Involved in solving defects raised by testing team.
- Worked in Agile team developing responsive web pages as per the requirements. Presented ideas for design improvements, participated in code reviews cross knowledge transfer sessions with peers.

Full Stack Developer Intern

Jan 2021 – May 2021

Redko LLC

California, UnitedStates

- Involved in building responsive UI components using ReactJs, React Native with backend as Firebase
- Analyzed the user needs and designed web applications. Worked with product owner to meet specification needs.
- Collaborated with other developers to design and optimize the code. Performed routine software maintenance.

Programmer Analyst

Dec 2018 – Dec 2019

Cognizant Technological Solutions

Hyderabad, India

- Redesigned the UI components for improving look and feel of software using Angular, ReactJS, HTML5, CSS3
- Experienced in building applications consuming **REST API's**. Participated in scrum-based team focused on agile
- Prepared testing scenarios like test plans, test data, test cases for functioning of UI components in TDD fashion.

Projects

Wealth Dashboard | Angular, Jenkins, Bitbucket, Invision

Feb 2022

Developed dashboard application required for internal monitoring and plotted the results in graphical view.

Fitness Tracker | Angular, Angular Material, Angular Fire, Firebase

• Built single page application where user practises fitness exercises, views fitness videos etc. and hosted on firebase.

RooBot | Django, ReactJs, CSS3, HTML5, Rasa, Artificial Intelligence, GIT

Nov 2020

• Developed a full-stack web application using with Flask serving a REST API with React as the front-end

Twitter Data Analysis and Visualization | Django, Python, HTML5, Spark, Scala

Jan 2020 – May 2020

• Used Tweepy API and Python to extract 200K tweets, analyzed them and wrote efficient queries to retrieve data and visualized in graphs, at end developed web application using Django to display them.

Technical Skills

Languages: Java, Python, C. JavaScript, HTML5/CSS3, DataStructures&Algorithms, Operating Systems

Frameworks: ReactJs, NodeJs, ExpressJs, Angular, JSON, Bootstrap, SpringBoot

Developer Tools: Git, Docker, Visual Studio, Android Studio, STS, Jupyter Notebook, Eclipse

Deployments: Heroku, Git Pages, Google Cloud Platform, Microsoft Azure, AWS

Databases: SQL,Oracle, Mongodb, Firebase, SQLite

ACTIVITIES AND AWARDS

Best Employee Award - TCS Udacity Nutanix Hybrid Cloud Scholarship - Udacity UMKC Virtual Hack-A-Roo Spring 2020 - UMKC

Mar 2022

Aug 2020

May 2020